AZEEZ BABARINDE

Data Analyst

Data Analyst with a background in science and research. Experienced in presenting complex information in an understandable and engaging way. Completed analysis projects across multiple fields, including health care, engineering, agriculture, ecommerce, logistics and tobacco.

■ babarindeazeez.s@gmail.com

Perlin, Germany

zeezki.github.io

+4915218174952

in linkedin.com/in/azeezbabarinde

github.com/zeezki

EDUCATION

Data Analytics Certification,

CareerFoundry

06/2021 – 10/2021 Berlin, Germany

Masters of Science in Environmental and Resource Management,

Brandenburg University of Technology 08/2019 – 07/2023 Cottbus Germany

Diploma in Web Design,

HIIT Plc

04/2016 - 07/2016 Ikeja, Nigeria

Bachelor of Agriculture (Soil Science and Land Management),

Federal University of Agriculture 09/2009 - 11/2014 Abeokuta, Nigeria

Computer Systems Technician (Diploma),

Michelon Computer Institute 10/2007 - 06/2008 Lagos, Nigeria

SKILLS / TOOLS

- Advanced Analytics
- Data Visualization (Tableau, Data studio, Power BI)
- MS Office (Excel, PowerPoint, Words, VBA)
- Google Workspace(Docs, Sheets, Slides)
- Python (Pandas, NumPy, Matplotlib, Scipy, Seaborn)
- SQL (GBQ, PostgreSQL)
- Story telling with data
- Machine Learning (Supervised and Unsupervised)
- Hypothesis testing
- Ticket Support (JIRA)
- HTML / CSS

LANGUAGES

English – *Native User* Deutsch – *A2*

WORK EXPERIENCE

Data Manager

JTI (Japan Tobacco International) Trier, Germany 01/2023 - Current

- Developed data extraction tool for SDS managers to reduce manual data entry time by over 95%
- Built a visualization tool to monitor the safety data sheets requests on various KPIs
- Created an automation tool to optimize manual chemical inventory calculation, reducing task time by over 90%

Business Analyst - Internship

Wayfair *Berlin, Germany* 07/2022 - 01/2023

- Provided excellent customer services and training on tooluse to Suppliers and warehouse managers for conversion.
- Built a visualizations tool to give visibility over late orders for the company's warehouse.

Data Analyst

ELALAN Construction Company

08/2021 - 02/2022

 Developed KPI to monitor company sales and decreased cost by 20%.

Data Analyst

Self-employed - Freelance 08/2020 - 08/2021

 Performed cleansing, processing, and validation on data to analyze, to ensure its quality.

Data Analyst

Stanfrey Engineering Limited 12/2016 - 07/2020

 Conveyed analysis findings through reports, dashboards, and visualizations, saving 10 hours of weekly manual reporting.

Web Analyst - Internship

HIIT Plc 08/2016 - 11/2016

Computer Science Teacher (National Youth Service)

N.K.S.T Girls secondary school 05/2015 - 05/2016

PROJECTS

EA Sports FIFA player ratings

